[
    {
      "section": 1,
      "question": "Every employee of your company has a Google account. Your operational team needs to manage a large number of instances on Compute Engine. Each member of this team needs only administrative access to the servers. Your security team wants to ensure that the deployment of credentials is operationally efficient and must be able to determine who accessed a given instance. What should you do?",
      "options": ["Generate a new SSH key pair. Give the private key to each member of your team. Configure the public key in the metadata of each instance.", "Generate a new SSH key pair. Give the private key to each member of your team. Configure the public key as a project-wide public SSH key in your Cloud Platform project and allow project-wide public SSH keys on each instance.", "Ask each member of the team to generate a new SSH key pair and to send you their public key. Use a configuration management tool to deploy those keys on each instance.",
        "Ask each member of the team to generate a new SSH key pair and to add the public key to their Google account. Grant the ג€compute.osAdminLoginג€ role to the Google group corresponding to this team."],
      "correctAnswer": "Ask each member of the team to generate a new SSH key pair and to add the public key to their Google account. Grant the ג€compute.osAdminLoginג€ role to the Google group corresponding to this team."
    },
    {
      "section": 1,
      "question": "You need to create a custom VPC with a single subnet. The subnet's range must be as large as possible. Which range should you use?",
      "options": ["0.0.0.0/0", "10.0.0.0/8", "172.16.0.0/12", "192.168.0.0/16"],
      "correctAnswer": "10.0.0.0/8"
    },
    {
        "section": 1,
        "question": "You want to select and configure a cost-effective solution for relational data on Google Cloud Platform. You are working with a small set of operational data in one geographic location. You need to support point-in-time recovery. What should you do?",
        "options": ["Select Cloud SQL (MySQL). Verify that the enable binary logging option is selected.", "Select Cloud SQL (MySQL). Select the create failover replicas option.", "Select Cloud Spanner. Set up your instance with 2 nodes.", "Select Cloud Spanner. Set up your instance as multi-regional"],
        "correctAnswer": "Select Cloud SQL (MySQL). Verify that the enable binary logging option is selected."
      },
      {
        "section": 1,
        "question": "You want to configure autohealing for network load balancing for a group of Compute Engine instances that run in multiple zones, using the fewest possible steps. You need to configure re-creation of VMs if they are unresponsive after 3 attempts of 10 seconds each. What should you do?",
        "options": ["Create an HTTP load balancer with a backend configuration that references an existing instance group. Set the health check to healthy (HTTP)", "Create an HTTP load balancer with a backend configuration that references an existing instance group. Define a balancing mode and set the maximum RPS to 10.", "Create a managed instance group. Set the Autohealing health check to healthy (HTTP)", "Create a managed instance group. Verify that the autoscaling setting is on."],
        "correctAnswer": "Create a managed instance group. Set the Autohealing health check to healthy (HTTP)"
      },
      {
        "section": 1,
        "question": "You are using multiple configurations for gcloud. You want to review the configured Kubernetes Engine cluster of an inactive configuration using the fewest possible steps. What should you do?",
        "options": ["Use gcloud config configurations describe to review the output.", "Use gcloud config configurations activate and gcloud config list to review the output.", "Use kubectl config get-contexts to review the output.", "Use kubectl config use-context and kubectl config view to review the output."],
        "correctAnswer": "Use kubectl config use-context and kubectl config view to review the output."
      },
      {
        "section": 1,
        "question": "Your company uses Cloud Storage to store application backup files for disaster recovery purposes. You want to follow Google's recommended practices. Which storage option should you use?",
        "options": ["Multi-Regional Storage", "Regional Storage", "Nearline Storage", "Coldline Storage"],
       "correctAnswer": "Coldline Storage"
      },
      {
        "section": 1,
        "question": "Several employees at your company have been creating projects with Cloud Platform and paying for it with their personal credit cards, which the company reimburses. The company wants to centralize all these projects under a single, new billing account. What should you do?",
        "options": ["Contact cloud-billing@google.com with your bank account details and request a corporate billing account for your company.", "Create a ticket with Google Support and wait for their call to share your credit card details over the phone.", "In the Google Platform Console, go to the Resource Manage and move all projects to the root Organizarion.", "In the Google Cloud Platform Console, create a new billing account and set up a payment method."],
        "correctAnswer": "In the Google Cloud Platform Console, create a new billing account and set up a payment method."
      },
      {
        "section": 1,
        "question": "You have an application that looks for its licensing server on the IP 10.0.3.21. You need to deploy the licensing server on Compute Engine. You do not want to change the configuration of the application and want the application to be able to reach the licensing server. What should you do?",
        "options": ["Reserve the IP 10.0.3.21 as a static internal IP address using gcloud and assign it to the licensing server.", "Reserve the IP 10.0.3.21 as a static public IP address using gcloud and assign it to the licensing server.", "Use the IP 10.0.3.21 as a custom ephemeral IP address and assign it to the licensing server.","Start the licensing server with an automatic ephemeral IP address, and then promote it to a static internal IP address."],
        "correctAnswer": "Reserve the IP 10.0.3.21 as a static internal IP address using gcloud and assign it to the licensing server."
      },
      {
        "section": 1,
        "question": "You want to configure autohealing for network load balancing for a group of Compute Engine instances that run in multiple zones, using the fewest possible steps. You need to configure re-creation of VMs if they are unresponsive after 3 attempts of 10 seconds each. What should you do?",
        "options": ["Create an HTTP load balancer with a backend configuration that references an existing instance group. Set the health check to healthy (HTTP)", "Create an HTTP load balancer with a backend configuration that references an existing instance group. Define a balancing mode and set the maximum RPS to 10.", "Create a managed instance group. Set the Autohealing health check to healthy (HTTP)", "Create a managed instance group. Verify that the autoscaling setting is on."],
        "correctAnswer": "Create a managed instance group. Set the Autohealing health check to healthy (HTTP)"
      },
      {
        "section": 1,
        "question": "You are deploying an application to App Engine. You want the number of instances to scale based on request rate. You need at least 3 unoccupied instances at all times. Which scaling type should you use?",
        "options": ["Use gcloud iam roles copy and specify the production project as the destination project.", "Use gcloud iam roles copy and specify your organization as the destination organization.", "In the Google Cloud Platform Console, use the 'create role from role' functionality.", "In the Google Cloud Platform Console, use the 'create role' functionality and select all applicable permissions."],
        "correctAnswer": "Use gcloud iam roles copy and specify the production project as the destination project."
      },
      {
        "section": 1,
        "question": "You need a dynamic way of provisioning VMs on Compute Engine. The exact specifications will be in a dedicated configuration file. You want to follow Google's recommended practices. Which method should you use?",
        "options": ["Deployment Manager", "Cloud Composer", "Managed Instance Group", "Unmanaged Instance Group"],
        "correctAnswer": "Deployment Manager"
      },
      {
        "section": 1,
        "question": "You have a Dockerfile that you need to deploy on Kubernetes Engine. What should you do?",
        "options": ["Use kubectl app deploy <dockerfilename>.", "Create a docker image from the Dockerfile and upload it to Container Registry. Create a Deployment YAML file to point to that image. Use kubectl to create the deployment with that file.", "Create a docker image from the Dockerfile and upload it to Cloud Storage. Create a Deployment YAML file to point to that image. Use kubectl to create the deployment with that file.", "Use gcloud app deploy <dockerfilename>."],
        "correctAnswer": "Create a docker image from the Dockerfile and upload it to Container Registry. Create a Deployment YAML file to point to that image. Use kubectl to create the deployment with that file."
      },
      {
        "section": 1,
        "question": "Your development team needs a new Jenkins server for their project. You need to deploy the server using the fewest steps possible. What should you do?",
        "options": ["Download and deploy the Jenkins Java WAR to App Engine Standard.", "Create a new Compute Engine instance and install Jenkins through the command line interface.", "Create a Kubernetes cluster on Compute Engine and create a deployment with the Jenkins Docker image.", "Use GCP Marketplace to launch the Jenkins solution."],
        "correctAnswer": "Use GCP Marketplace to launch the Jenkins solution."
      },
      {
        "section": 1,
        "question": "You need to update a deployment in Deployment Manager without any resource downtime in the deployment. Which command should you use?",
        "options": ["gcloud deployment-manager deployments create --config <deployment-config-path>", "gcloud deployment-manager deployments update --config <deployment-config-path>", "gcloud deployment-manager resources create --config <deployment-config-path>", "gcloud deployment-manager resources update --config <deployment-config-path>"],
        "correctAnswer": "gcloud deployment-manager deployments update --config <deployment-config-path>"
      },
      {
        "section": 1,
        "question": "You need to run an important query in BigQuery but expect it to return a lot of records. You want to find out how much it will cost to run the query. You are using on-demand pricing. What should you do?",
        "options": ["Arrange to switch to Flat-Rate pricing for this query, then move back to on-demand.", "Use the command line to run a dry run query to estimate the number of bytes read. Then convert that bytes estimate to dollars using the Pricing Calculator.", "Use the command line to run a dry run query to estimate the number of bytes returned. Then convert that bytes estimate to dollars using the Pricing Calculator.", "Run a select count (*) to get an idea of how many records your query will look through. Then convert that number of rows to dollars using the Pricing Calculator."],
        "correctAnswer": "Use the command line to run a dry run query to estimate the number of bytes read. Then convert that bytes estimate to dollars using the Pricing Calculator."
      },
      {
        "section": 1,
        "question": "You have a single binary application that you want to run on Google Cloud Platform. You decided to automatically scale the application based on underlying infrastructure CPU usage. Your organizational policies require you to use virtual machines directly. You need to ensure that the application scaling is operationally efficient and completed as quickly as possible. What should you do?",
        "options": ["Create a Google Kubernetes Engine cluster, and use horizontal pod autoscaling to scale the application.", "Create an instance template, and use the template in a managed instance group with autoscaling configured.", "Create an instance template, and use the template in a managed instance group that scales up and down based on the time of day.", "Use a set of third-party tools to build automation around scaling the application up and down, based on Stackdriver CPU usage monitoring."],
        "correctAnswer": "Create an instance template, and use the template in a managed instance group with autoscaling configured."
      },
      {
        "section": 1,
        "question": "You are analyzing Google Cloud Platform service costs from three separate projects. You want to use this information to create service cost estimates by service type, daily and monthly, for the next six months using standard query syntax. What should you do?",
        "options": ["Export your bill to a Cloud Storage bucket, and then import into Cloud Bigtable for analysis.", "Export your bill to a Cloud Storage bucket, and then import into Google Sheets for analysis.", "Export your transactions to a local file, and perform analysis with a desktop tool.", "Export your bill to a BigQuery dataset, and then write time window-based SQL queries for analysis."],
        "correctAnswer": "Export your bill to a BigQuery dataset, and then write time window-based SQL queries for analysis."
      },
      {
        "section": 1,
        "question": "You need to set up a policy so that videos stored in a specific Cloud Storage Regional bucket are moved to Coldline after 90 days, and then deleted after one year from their creation. How should you set up the policy?",
        "options": [
          "Use Cloud Storage Object Lifecycle Management using Age conditions with SetStorageClass and Delete actions. Set the SetStorageClass action to 90 days and the Delete action to 275 days (365 - 90)",
          "Use Cloud Storage Object Lifecycle Management using Age conditions with SetStorageClass and Delete actions. Set the SetStorageClass action to 90 days and the Delete action to 365 days.",
          "Use gsutil rewrite and set the Delete action to 275 days (365 - 90).",
          "Use gsutil rewrite and set the Delete action to 365 days."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Use Cloud Storage Object Lifecycle Management using Age conditions with SetStorageClass and Delete actions. Set the SetStorageClass action to 90 days and the Delete action to 365 days."
      },
       {
        "section": 1,
        "question": "You have a Linux VM that must connect to Cloud SQL. You created a service account with the appropriate access rights. You want to make sure that the VM uses this service account instead of the default Compute Engine service account. What should you do?",
        "options": ["When creating the VM via the web console, specify the service account under the 'Identity and API Access' section.", "Download a JSON Private Key for the service account. On the Project Metadata, add that JSON as the value for the key compute-engine-service- account.", "Download a JSON Private Key for the service account. On the Custom Metadata of the VM, add that JSON as the value for the key compute-engine- service-account.", "Download a JSON Private Key for the service account. After creating the VM, ssh into the VM and save the JSON under ~/.gcloud/compute-engine-service- account.json."],
        "correctAnswer": "When creating the VM via the web console, specify the service account under the 'Identity and API Access' section."
      },{
        "section": 1,
        "question": "You created an instance of SQL Server 2017 on Compute Engine to test features in the new version. You want to connect to this instance using the fewest number of steps. What should you do?",
        "options": [" Install a RDP client on your desktop. Verify that a firewall rule for port 3389 exists.", "Install a RDP client in your desktop. Set a Windows username and password in the GCP Console. Use the credentials to log in to the instance.", "Set a Windows password in the GCP Console. Verify that a firewall rule for port 22 exists. Click the RDP button in the GCP Console and supply the credentials to log in.", "Set a Windows username and password in the GCP Console. Verify that a firewall rule for port 3389 exists. Click the RDP button in the GCP Console, and supply the credentials to log in."],
        "correctAnswer": "Install a RDP client in your desktop. Set a Windows username and password in the GCP Console. Use the credentials to log in to the instance."
      },{
        "section": 1,
        "question": "You have one GCP account running in your default region and zone and another account running in a non-default region and zone. You want to start a newCompute Engine instance in these two Google Cloud Platform accounts using the command line interface. What should you do?",
        "options": ["Create two configurations using gcloud config configurations create [NAME]. Run gcloud config configurations activate [NAME] to switch between accounts when running the commands to start the Compute Engine instances.", "Create two configurations using gcloud config configurations create [NAME]. Run gcloud configurations list to start the Compute Engine instances.", "Activate two configurations using gcloud configurations activate [NAME]. Run gcloud config list to start the Compute Engine instances.", "Activate two configurations using gcloud configurations activate [NAME]. Run gcloud configurations list to start the Compute Engine instances."],
        "correctAnswer": "Create two configurations using gcloud config configurations create [NAME]. Run gcloud config configurations activate [NAME] to switch between accounts when running the commands to start the Compute Engine instances."
      },
      {
        "section": 1,
        "question": "You significantly changed a complex Deployment Manager template and want to confirm that the dependencies of all defined resources are properly met before committing it to the project. You want the most rapid feedback on your changes. What should you do?",
        "options": ["Use granular logging statements within a Deployment Manager template authored in Python.", "Monitor activity of the Deployment Manager execution on the Stackdriver Logging page of the GCP Console.", "Execute the Deployment Manager template against a separate project with the same configuration, and monitor for failures.", "Execute the Deployment Manager template in the same project with the '-preview' option enabled, and monitor the status of interconnected resources."],
        "correctAnswer": "Execute the Deployment Manager template in the same project with the '-preview' option enabled, and monitor the status of interconnected resources."
      },{
        "section": 1,
        "question": "You have a project for your App Engine application that serves a development environment. The required testing has succeeded and you want to create a new project to serve as your production environment. What should you do?",
        "options": ["Use gcloud to create the new project, and then deploy your application to the new project.", "Use gcloud to create the new project and to copy the deployed application to the new project.", "Create a Deployment Manager configuration file that copies the current App Engine deployment into a new project.", "Deploy your application again using gcloud and specify the project parameter with the new project name to create the new project."],
        "correctAnswer": "Use gcloud to create the new project, and then deploy your application to the new project."
      },{
        "section": 1,
        "question": "You need to configure IAM access audit logging in BigQuery for external auditors. You want to follow Google-recommended practices. What should you do?",
        "options": ["Add the auditors group to the 'logging.viewer' and 'bigQuery.dataViewer' predefined IAM roles.", "Add the auditors group to two new custom IAM roles.", "Add the auditor user accounts to the 'logging.viewer' and 'bigQuery.dataViewer' predefined IAM roles.", "Add the auditor user accounts to two new custom IAM roles."],
        "correctAnswer": "Add the auditors group to the 'logging.viewer' and 'bigQuery.dataViewer' predefined IAM roles."
      },{
        "section": 1,
        "question": "You need to set up permissions for a set of Compute Engine instances to enable them to write data into a particular Cloud Storage bucket. You want to follow Google-recommended practices. What should you do?",
        "options": ["Create a service account with an access scope. Use the access scope 'https://www.googleapis.com/auth/devstorage.write_only'.", "Create a service account with an access scope. Use the access scope 'https://www.googleapis.com/auth/cloud-platform'.", "Create a service account and add it to the IAM role 'storage.objectCreator' for that bucket.", "Create a service account and add it to the IAM role 'storage.objectAdmin' for that bucket."],
        "correctAnswer": "Create a service account and add it to the IAM role 'storage.objectCreator' for that bucket."
      },{
        "section": 1,
        "question": "You have sensitive data stored in three Cloud Storage buckets and have enabled data access logging. You want to verify activities for a particular user for these buckets, using the fewest possible steps. You need to verify the addition of metadata labels and which files have been viewed from those buckets. What should you do?",
        "options": ["Using the GCP Console, filter the Activity log to view the information.", "Using the GCP Console, filter the Stackdriver log to view the information.", "View the bucket in the Storage section of the GCP Console.", "Create a trace in Stackdriver to view the information."],
        "correctAnswer": "Using the GCP Console, filter the Activity log to view the information."
      },{
        "section": 1,
        "question": "You are the project owner of a GCP project and want to delegate control to colleagues to manage buckets and files in Cloud Storage. You want to follow Google- recommended practices. Which IAM roles should you grant your colleagues?",
        "options": ["Project Editor", "Storage Admin", "Storage Object Admin", "Storage Object Creator"],
        "correctAnswer": "Storage Admin"
      },{
        "section": 1,
        "question": "You have an object in a Cloud Storage bucket that you want to share with an external company. The object contains sensitive data. You want access to the content to be removed after four hours. The external company does not have a Google account to which you can grant specific user-based access privileges. You want to use the most secure method that requires the fewest steps. What should you do?",
        "options": ["Create a signed URL with a four-hour expiration and share the URL with the company.", "Set object access to 'public' and use object lifecycle management to remove the object after four hours.", "Configure the storage bucket as a static website and furnish the object's URL to the company. Delete the object from the storage bucket after four hours.", "Create a new Cloud Storage bucket specifically for the external company to access. Copy the object to that bucket. Delete the bucket after four hours have passed."],
        "correctAnswer": "Create a signed URL with a four-hour expiration and share the URL with the company."
      },{
        "section": 1,
        "question": "You are creating a Google Kubernetes Engine (GKE) cluster with a cluster autoscaler feature enabled. You need to make sure that each node of the cluster will run a monitoring pod that sends container metrics to a third-party monitoring solution. What should you do?",
        "options": ["Deploy the monitoring pod in a StatefulSet object.", "Deploy the monitoring pod in a DaemonSet object.", "Reference the monitoring pod in a Deployment object.", " Reference the monitoring pod in a cluster initializer at the GKE cluster creation time."],
        "correctAnswer": "Deploy the monitoring pod in a DaemonSet object."
      },{
        "section": 1,
        "question": "You want to send and consume Cloud Pub/Sub messages from your App Engine application. The Cloud Pub/Sub API is currently disabled. You will use a service account to authenticate your application to the API. You want to make sure your application can use Cloud Pub/Sub. What should you do?",
        "options": ["Enable the Cloud Pub/Sub API in the API Library on the GCP Console.", "Rely on the automatic enablement of the Cloud Pub/Sub API when the Service Account accesses it.", "Use Deployment Manager to deploy your application. Rely on the automatic enablement of all APIs used by the application being deployed.", "Grant the App Engine Default service account the role of Cloud Pub/Sub Admin. Have your application enable the API on the first connection to Cloud Pub/ Sub."],
        "correctAnswer": "Enable the Cloud Pub/Sub API in the API Library on the GCP Console."
      },{
        "section": 1,
        "question": "You need to monitor resources that are distributed over different projects in Google Cloud Platform. You want to consolidate reporting under the same Stackdriver Monitoring dashboard. What should you do?",
        "options": ["Use Shared VPC to connect all projects, and link Stackdriver to one of the projects.", "For each project, create a Stackdriver account. In each project, create a service account for that project and grant it the role of Stackdriver Account Editor in all other projects.", "Configure a single Stackdriver account, and link all projects to the same account.", "Configure a single Stackdriver account for one of the projects. In Stackdriver, create a Group and add the other project names as criteria for that Group."],
        "correctAnswer": "Configure a single Stackdriver account, and link all projects to the same account."
      },{
        "section": 1,
        "question": "  You are deploying an application to a Compute Engine VM in a managed instance group. The application must be running at all times, but only a single instance of the VM should run per GCP project. How should you configure the instance group?",
        "options": ["Set autoscaling to On, set the minimum number of instances to 1, and then set the maximum number of instances to 1.", "Set autoscaling to Off, set the minimum number of instances to 1, and then set the maximum number of instances to 1.", "Set autoscaling to On, set the minimum number of instances to 1, and then set the maximum number of instances to 2.", "Set autoscaling to Off, set the minimum number of instances to 1, and then set the maximum number of instances to 2."],
        "correctAnswer": "Set autoscaling to On, set the minimum number of instances to 1, and then set the maximum number of instances to 1."
      },{
        "section": 1,
        "question": "You want to verify the IAM users and roles assigned within a GCP project named my-project. What should you do?",
        "options": ["Run gcloud iam roles list. Review the output section.", "Run gcloud iam service-accounts list. Review the output section.", "Navigate to the project and then to the IAM section in the GCP Console. Review the members and roles.", "Navigate to the project and then to the Roles section in the GCP Console. Review the roles and status."],
        "correctAnswer": "Navigate to the project and then to the IAM section in the GCP Console. Review the members and roles."
      },{
        "section": 1,
        "question": "You need to create a new billing account and then link it with an existing Google Cloud Platform project. What should you do?",
        "options": ["Verify that you are Project Billing Manager for the GCP project. Update the existing project to link it to the existing billing account.", "Verify that you are Project Billing Manager for the GCP project. Create a new billing account and link the new billing account to the existing project. ", " Verify that you are Billing Administrator for the billing account. Create a new project and link the new project to the existing billing account.", "Verify that you are Billing Administrator for the billing account. Update the existing project to link it to the existing billing account."],
        "correctAnswer": "Verify that you are Project Billing Manager for the GCP project. Create a new billing account and link the new billing account to the existing project. "
      },{
        "section": 1,
        "question": "You have one project called proj-sa where you manage all your service accounts. You want to be able to use a service account from this project to take snapshots of VMs running in another project called proj-vm. What should you do?",
        "options": ["Download the private key from the service account, and add it to each VMs custom metadata.", "Download the private key from the service account, and add the private key to each VM's SSH keys.", "Grant the service account the IAM Role of Compute Storage Admin in the project called proj-vm.", "When creating the VMs, set the service account's API scope for Compute Engine to read/write."],
        "correctAnswer": "Grant the service account the IAM Role of Compute Storage Admin in the project called proj-vm."
      },{
        "section": 1,
        "question": "You created a Google Cloud Platform project with an App Engine application inside the project. You initially configured the application to be served from the us- central region. Now you want the application to be served from the asia-northeast1 region. What should you do?",
        "options": ["Change the default region property setting in the existing GCP project to asia-northeast1.", "Change the region property setting in the existing App Engine application from us-central to asia-northeast1.", "Create a second App Engine application in the existing GCP project and specify asia-northeast1 as the region to serve your application.", "Create a new GCP project and create an App Engine application inside this new project. Specify asia-northeast1 as the region to serve your application."],
        "correctAnswer": "Create a new GCP project and create an App Engine application inside this new project. Specify asia-northeast1 as the region to serve your application."
      }
    
  ]
